import { DialogueQuestion } from '@/types/quiz';
import { addGrammarName } from '@/lib/quiz/helpers';
// 이거, 그거, 저거, 책, 펜, 가방, 커피, 물, 책상, 의자, 빵, 우유, 핸드폰

const questions: Omit<DialogueQuestion, 'grammarName'>[] = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '이거는 책이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This is a book.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '책', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '이거는 펜이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This is a pen.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '펜', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '이거는 가방이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This is a bag.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '가방', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '이거는 커피예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This is coffee.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '커피', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '이거는 물이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This is water.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '물', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '이거는 책상이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This is a desk.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '책상', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '이거는 의자예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This is a chair.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '의자', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '이거는 빵이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This is a bread.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '빵', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '이거는 우유예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This is milk.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '우유', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '이거는 핸드폰이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This is a phone.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '핸드폰', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '그거는 책이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a book.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '그거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '책', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '그거는 펜이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a pen.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '그거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '펜', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '그거는 가방이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a bag.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '그거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '가방', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '그거는 커피예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is coffee.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '그거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '커피', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '그거는 물이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is water.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '그거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '물', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '그거는 책상이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a desk.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '그거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '책상', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '그거는 의자예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a chair.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '그거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '의자', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '그거는 빵이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a bread.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '그거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '빵', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '그거는 우유예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is milk.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '그거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '우유', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: '이거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is this?',
    answer: '그거는 핸드폰이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a phone.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '그거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '핸드폰', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question: '저거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is that?',
    answer: '저거는 책이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a book.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '책', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question: '저거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is that?',
    answer: '저거는 펜이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a pen.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '펜', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question: '저거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is that?',
    answer: '저거는 가방이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a bag.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '가방', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: '저거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is that?',
    answer: '저거는 커피예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is coffee.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '커피', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question: '저거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is that?',
    answer: '저거는 물이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is water.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '물', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question: '저거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is that?',
    answer: '저거는 책상이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a desk.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '책상', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question: '저거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is that?',
    answer: '저거는 의자예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a chair.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '의자', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question: '저거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is that?',
    answer: '저거는 빵이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a bread.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '빵', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question: '저거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is that?',
    answer: '저거는 우유예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is milk.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '우유', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question: '저거는 뭐예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'What is that?',
    answer: '저거는 핸드폰이에요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That is a phone.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '2', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '3', content: '핸드폰', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '4', content: '이에요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question: '이 책은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose book is this?',
    answer: '이 책은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This book is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '책', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question: '이 펜은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose pen is this?',
    answer: '이 펜은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This pen is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '펜', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    question: '이 가방은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose bag is this?',
    answer: '이 가방은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This bag is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '가방', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question: '이 커피는 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose coffee is this?',
    answer: '이 커피는 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This coffee is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '커피', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    question: '이 물은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose water is this?',
    answer: '이 물은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This water is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '물', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question: '이 책상은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose desk is this?',
    answer: '이 책상은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This desk is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '책상', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question: '이 의자는 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose chair is this?',
    answer: '이 의자는 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This chair is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '의자', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: '이 빵은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose bread is this?',
    answer: '이 빵은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This bread is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '빵', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question: '이 우유는 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose milk is this?',
    answer: '이 우유는 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This milk is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '우유', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    question: '이 핸드폰은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose phone is this?',
    answer: '이 핸드폰은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'This phone is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '이', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '핸드폰', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 41,
    question: '저 책은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose book is that?',
    answer: '저 책은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That book is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '책', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 42,
    question: '저 펜은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose pen is that?',
    answer: '저 펜은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That pen is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '펜', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 43,
    question: '저 가방은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose bag is that?',
    answer: '저 가방은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That bag is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '가방', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 44,
    question: '저 커피는 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose coffee is that?',
    answer: '저 커피는 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That coffee is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '커피', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 45,
    question: '저 물은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose water is that?',
    answer: '저 물은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That water is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '물', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 46,
    question: '저 책상은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose desk is that?',
    answer: '저 책상은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That desk is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '책상', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 47,
    question: '저 의자는 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose chair is that?',
    answer: '저 의자는 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That chair is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '의자', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 48,
    question: '저 빵은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose bread is that?',
    answer: '저 빵은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That bread is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '빵', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 49,
    question: '저 우유는 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose milk is that?',
    answer: '저 우유는 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That milk is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '우유', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '는', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 50,
    question: '저 핸드폰은 누구 거예요?',
    questionTranslation: 'Whose phone is that?',
    answer: '저 핸드폰은 제 거예요.',
    answerTranslation: 'That phone is mine.',
items: [
      { id: '1', content: '저', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '2', content: '핸드폰', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '3', content: '은', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '4', content: '제', combineWithNext: false },
      { id: '5', content: '거', combineWithNext: true },
      { id: '6', content: '예요.' },
    ],
  },
];

export const demonstrativeQuestions = addGrammarName(questions, 'demonstratives');
